<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Juan Pablo Pino</title>
    <link href="http://jp-pino.github.io/" />
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://jp-pino.github.io/blog/feed.atom" />
    <updated>2019-08-18T19:01:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jp-pino.github.io/blog/feed.atom</id>
    <author>
        <name>Juan Pablo Pino Bravo</name>
    </author>
                <entry>
    <id>http://jp-pino.github.io/blog/ieee-comments</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://jp-pino.github.io/blog/ieee-comments" />
    <title>Image Processing</title>
    <published>2019-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Juan Pablo Pino</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Comments on &amp;quot;Relative CNN-RNN: Learning Relative Atmospheric Visibility From Images&amp;quot; by Yang You &amp;amp; Cewu Lu from &amp;quot;IEEE Transactions on Image Processing&amp;quot;
Reading this paper, it becomes clear that image processing is a field that may......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p><em>Comments on <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8412582"><strong>&quot;Relative CNN-RNN: Learning Relative Atmospheric Visibility From Images&quot;</strong></a> by Yang You &amp; Cewu Lu from <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/tocresult.jsp?isnumber=8468142&amp;punumber=83">&quot;IEEE Transactions on Image Processing&quot;</a></em></p>
<p>Reading this paper, it becomes clear that image processing is a field that may have far-reaching impacts on our lives. This paper proposes a method for estimating relative visibility from images using a relative CNN-RNN model. According to the paper, this model combines a Convolutional Neural Networks with a Recursive Neural Network which allows it to analyze the images with seven different attention regions in the images. As the authors mention, this approach produces good results in atmospheric visibility estimation and if implemented in a large-scale setup (e.g. using geo-tagged images uploaded to the web), it becomes much more affordable than the expensive scientific equipment used in very sparse weather observatories. <strong><em>Image processing</em></strong> and <strong><em>Robotic Vision</em></strong>, are clearly fields that offer new and innovative solutions to everyday problems today, and in the years to come. </p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>http://jp-pino.github.io/blog/aes-file-encryption</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://jp-pino.github.io/blog/aes-file-encryption" />
    <title>AES</title>
    <published>2019-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Juan Pablo Pino</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">As a final project for the course &amp;quot;Computer Architecture&amp;quot;, Juan Manuel Ledesma and I designed a device that could cypher and decypher files using the Rijndael algorithm implementation of the Advanced Encryption Standard....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>As a final project for the course &quot;Computer Architecture&quot;, <a href="#">Juan Manuel Ledesma</a> and I designed a device that could cypher and decypher files using the Rijndael algorithm implementation of the Advanced Encryption Standard.</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>http://jp-pino.github.io/blog/mopiOS</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://jp-pino.github.io/blog/mopiOS" />
    <title>mopiOS</title>
    <published>2019-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Juan Pablo Pino</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">As a final project for the course EE445M &amp;quot;Embedded and Real-Time Operating Systems Laboratory&amp;quot; at UT Austin, Cole Morgan and I started developing our own RTOS implementation. mopiOS is still a work in progress and I&#039;m currently working on......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>As a final project for the course EE445M &quot;Embedded and Real-Time Operating Systems Laboratory&quot; at UT Austin, <a href="https://github.com/coleamorgan">Cole Morgan</a> and I started developing our own RTOS implementation. <a href="https://github.com/jp-pino/mopiOS">mopiOS</a> is still a work in progress and I'm currently working on porting it to other microcontrollers and adding more functionality to it.</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
    </feed>
